Guide to the Residential Child Care Project records, 1981-1997.
Residential Child Care Project records, 1981-1997.
- The Human Ecology of Child Maltreatment: A Conceptual Model for Research by James Garbarino, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- High-Risk Neighborhoods and High-Risk Families: The Human Ecology of Child Maltreatment by James Garbarino and Deborah Sherman, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Shaping a Role for State Child Protective Services in Institutional Child Maltreatment by George Thomas, Presented at the New York State Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, Albany, New York, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Investigation of Child Abuse and Neglect In Out of Home Care (IOHC), Residential Child Care Project, Family Life Development Center (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Supervisory Proficiency Tests, Series I, Employee Motivation (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Motivation Assessment Inventory; An Analysis of Motives to Work by Dennis Kinlaw (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Employee Motivation Inventory (Box 5, Folder 25)
- A Proposal for an Agreement between the Family life Development Center and the American Humane Association, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Child Welfare Institute Training Programs, Memorandum, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Criminal Investigation by Charles Bozza, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Balloon Picture (Box 5, Folder 26)
- In Out of Home Care, Foster/Day Care Notes (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Behavior Management of the Aggressive Client (BMAC), Participant's Manual, Direct Care Staff, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Behavior Management of the Aggressive Client (BMAC) Training Thoughts, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Broome Developmental Services, Policy and Procedures, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Intervention for Self-Injurious Behavior, Illustrated Manual (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Nonviolent Crisis Intervention, A Two Tape Series Focusing On Therapeutic Management of Disruptive and Assaultive Behavior, Crisis Prevention Institute (Box 5, Folder 27)
- St. Catherine's Center for Children, Therapeutic Crisis Intervention Training Test (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Interview with Jim Lawson, Connors Group Home, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Quality of Care Questionnaire, Institutional Self-Assessment, Residential Child Care Project, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Syllabus for Phase I, Defensive Tactics, Crisis Control with Aikido, Inc., by Richard Rood, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Testimony Before the US House of Representatives Select Education Subcommittee, Oversight Hearings on the Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention and Treatment Act of 1974, As Amended, Concerning the Matter of "Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect", by George Thomas, Appendix I-IV, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Working Papers on the Protection, Care, and Development of Children in Residential Placements by George Thomas (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Social Services Administration, Maryland Department of Human Resources, Maryland Institutional Abuse Project, Final Report, Prepared by Michael Drummond, John Kardys, Philip King, and Adrienne Siegel, A, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Social Services Administration, Maryland Department of Human Resources, Maryland Institutional Abuse Project, Final Report, Prepared by Michael Drummond, John Kardys, Philip King, and Adrienne Siegel, B, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Welcome by Michael Nunno and Constance Galster, Residential Child Care Project, Family Life Development Center (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Investigation of Child Abuse and Neglect In Out of Home Care Form, Texas (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Correspondence with Ohio State University College of Social Work, Nolan Rindfleisch, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Protecting the Child in Residential Group Care...Ohio by Virginia Colson (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Medical Log; Proposed Critical Incident Report; Proposed Daily Logging Form; Protecting the Child in Residential Group Care Definitions (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Investigating Institutional Abuse and Neglect (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Institutional Child Protection Project, Notes and News, Ohio State University College of Social Work, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- A Survey of Child Protection Agencies, Second Draft, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- A Survey of Child Protection Agencies (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Identification, Management, and Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect in Residential Facilities, Project Proposal by Nolan Rindfleisch and Keith Kilty (Box 6, Folder 1)
- The Child Protection Agency Survey: A State and Local View by Nolan Rindfleisch and Donna Hicho, Institutional Child Protection Project, Ohio State University College of Social Work, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Organizational Factors in Child Protection in Residential Child Care Institutions, Project Proposal, Indiana University School of Social Work (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Preliminary Findings on the Placement of Abused Children in Residential Institutions, Residential Child Care Study, Indiana University School of Social Work (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Project Utah, Overview, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- The End of the Line, Report on the Worcester Secure Treatment Unit, Task Force on Institutional Abuse (Box 6, Folder 2)
- The Worcester Telegram Series on the Worcester Secure Treatment Unit, Task Force on Institutional Abuse, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- A Brief History, Task Force on Institutional Abuse (Box 6, Folder 2)
- State Youth Facilities Called Inhumane, Boston Globe, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Press Packet, Task Force on Institutional Abuse, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Report on Plummer Home for Boys, Prepared by Region III Institutional Review Committee, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- The Public and Community Service Program by Sanford Kravitz, Stowe Hausner, and Judy Schiffer, School of Social Welfare, State University of New York at Stony Brook (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Child Care Workers Training Program, School of Social Welfare, State University of New York at Stony Brook (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Investigation of Institutional Abuse and Neglect, Casework Policy and Procedures, New Jersey Department of Human Services, Division of Youth and Family Services, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Child Abuse and Neglect in Residential Institutions, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Child Abuse and Neglect Guidelines for the Division of Mental Health and Hospitals (Box 6, Folder 3)
- First Letter to All State Institutions from New Jersey Institutional Abuse Project, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Training on Child Abuse and Neglect in Institutions, New Jersey Institutional Abuse Project, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Participant Questionnaire; Conference Evaluation Form (morning and afternoon), New Jersey Institutional Abuse Conference (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Dealing with Agitated Clients (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Child Abuse and Neglect Reporting Guidelines, New Jersey Division of Mental Retardation and Division of Youth and Family Services, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Correspondence with New Jersey Department of Human Services, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Reporting of Suspected Child Abuse or Neglect in a Public or Private Facility, Administrative Order 3:05, New Jersey Department of Institutions and Agencies, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Policies and Procedures Regarding Institutional Child Abuse, New Jersey Department of Corrections, Juvenile Detention and Monitoring Unit, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Manual of Standards for Juvenile Detention Facilities, New Jersey Department of Corrections, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect in New Jersey: 1978-1980 by Gregory Smiles, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect: A Training Guide for Child Care Staff in Residential Institutions by Gregory Smiles, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- A Contemporary Definition of Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect by George Thomas, Presented at the Regional Conference on Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect, University of Iowa (Box 6, Folder 4)
- A Technology for Preventing Institutional Child Maltreatment: The Competency Oriented Behavior Rating System for Child and Youth Serving Institutions (COBRS) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Handbook for Understanding and Preventing Abuse and Neglect of Children in Out-of-Home Care, San Francisco Child Abuse Council and Department of Social Services Pilot Project, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Institutional Abuse by Eliana Gil (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Region IX Adds Institutional Abuse Component, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Module One: The Worker, Draft Outline (With Activities), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Referral for Group Care Services, Barry C., 8 years old (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Notes on the Basic Child Care Curriculum Meeting in D.C., 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Kerness Project Correspondence with New York State Department of Social Services, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Child Abuse and Neglect in New York State Foster Care Institutions, Project Manuscript, Washington D.C., 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- New York State Institutional Abuse to Be Studied, Research in Review, Department of Social Services Newsletter, No.11, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Model Response System, Outline (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Model Incident Report Form (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Model Internal Investigation report (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Reporting Institutional Abuse, Neglect, and Maltreatment to the Regional Office (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Model Response System, Narrative (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Child Abuse in New York State Foster Care Institutions, Notice of Research Project, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Senate Subcommittee on Child Abuse, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Progress Report Summary (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Relationships Among Child Care Professionals: A Model of Collaborative Supervision by Richard Goldman and Abbey Manburg, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Teaching and Training As A Facet of Supervision of Care Staff: An Overview by Henry Maier, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Symposium: Supervising Child Care Personnel by E. A. Baker, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- The Use of Sociogram Data in Staff Supervision by Gillian Doherty, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- A Systematic Supervisory Procedure for Child Care Training by P. David Kurtz, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- The Relationship Between Perceived Supervisory Behavior and Caregivers' Behavior in Child Care by Laurel Montgomery and Carol Seefeldt, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- A Supervisory Model for Child Care by William Rowe and Richard Sheilds (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Supervision of Child Care Staff by Raymond Fant and Andrew Ross, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Program and Evaluative Techniques and Fundamentals for the Child Care Supervisor by Amy Maggio (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Job Satisfaction and Organizational Commitment Among Child and Youth Care Workers by Mark Kreuger, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Authoritarianism, Dogmatism, and Coercion in Child Caring Institutions: A Study of Staff Attitudes by Kenneth Krause, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Prevention of Institutional Abuse Project, Memorandum, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- A Proposal for an Innovative Traineeship Program Leading to a Master's Degree in Social Work for Bachelor's Level Child Care Workers, Prepared by Elizabeth Dane and Robert Salmon, Hunter College of Social Work, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- I C/AN Make A Difference, Prevention Forum Series II and III, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Handouts; Series Brochures (Box 6, Folder 8)
- I C/AN Make A Difference, Prevention Forum Series IV, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- I C/AN Prevention Forum Series Program notes, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Overview of Past Forums, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Agenda of Legal Issues Outline (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Alternative Program Associates brochure (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Safety Mechanics: Introduction (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Institutional Abuse Prevention Symposium Memorandum, Correspondence by Preston Clark with IAP Staff, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with Robert Martin, University of Victoria, BC, Canada, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Child Care Etc.: An Educators' and Trainers' Cooperative, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Participant's Manual, Part I, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Training of Trainers in Therapeutic Crisis Intervention for the Child Care Worker, Instructor's Manual (Box 6, Folder 11)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Investigation In Out of Home Care, Guidebook, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Toward an Operational Definition of Institutional Abuse/Neglect: A Study of Assessed Severity of Institutional Abuse/Neglect by Joel Raab and Nolan Rindfleisch, prepared for presentation at the Fourth International Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, Paris, France, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- A Competency Oriented Behavior Rating System for Youth Serving Institutions (CORBS) (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Correspondence with Micheal Drummond of the Maryland Institutional Abuse Project, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Will Tomorrow be Another Day for Child Protective Services, or Just Another Today? by George Thomas, prepared for presentation at the Fourth National Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, Los Angeles, CA, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Working Papers on the Protection, Care, and Development of Children in Residential Placements by George Thomas (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Correspondence with Kevin Barrett of the Policy Development Department, National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, London, UK, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Experience of Child Abuse in Residential Care and Educational Placement: Results of A National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children Survey by Helen Westcott and Maria Clement, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Abuse in the Care System: A Pilot Study by the National Association of Young People in Care by Mary Moss, Sarah Sharpe, and Chris Fay (Box 6, Folder 13)
- The Abuse of Children In Out of Home Care by Michael Nunno and Nolan Rindfleisch (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Progress and Issues in the Implementation of the 1984 Out of Home Care Protection Amendment by Nolan Rindfleisch and Michael Nunno (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Child Abuse and Neglect Reporting and Investigation: Policy Guidelines for Decision Making by Douglas Besharov (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Care and Treatment Program Behavior Rating Scale Manual (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Standards for Child Protective Services Staff: Legislative Proposals (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Correspondence with Cathy Wright, New York State, Department of Social Services, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- The Changing Characteristics of Children in Social Services Funded Group Residential Programs, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Keeping Children's Need Paramount: A New Era of Accountability and Opportunity for Group Residential Services by George Thomas (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Protecting Children from Maltreatment After Residential Placement: The Impact of the Recent Social Reform Movement and Its Aftermath by George Thomas (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect And the Role of Child Protective Services (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Perspectives on Child Maltreatment in the Mid '80's, US Department of Health and Human Services (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Patient Abuse and Mistreatment in Psychiatric Centers: A Policy for Reporting Apparent Crimes To and Response By Law Enforcement Agencies, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- A Report on A Survey of the Indicated Reports of Child Maltreatment and Sexual Abuse in Day Care Settings in New York State, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Institutional Child Protection Project, Columbus Conference Information, Preventing Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect, Columbus, OH, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Legal Response: Child Advocacy and Protection, Volume 2, Number 3, Spring, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Statement of Mary Lynn Walker before the Committee on Education and Labor, Subcommittee on Select Education U.S. House of Representatives Concerning The Abuse of Children In Institutions, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Maryland Institutional Abuse Project, Final Report, prepared by Michael Drummond, John Kardys, Philip King, Adrienne Siegel, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- New York State Abandons Victims of Institutional Child Abuse, prepared by New York State Senator Franz Leichter (D-L, Manhattan, Bronx) and Micheal Skrak, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Out of Home Care: An Agenda for the Nineties, Report and Recommendations of the Child Welfare League of America Task Force on Out-of-Home Care by Robert Barker and Robert Aptekar, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Joint Investigations of Child Abuse, Report of a Symposium, National Institute of Justice Office for Victims of Crime Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention and National Center on Child Abuse & Neglect, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Reviewing the Literature on Child Maltreatment in Out of Home Care: An Ecological Perspective by Michael Nunno (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Drawer 2: Archived Special Topic Files (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Protective Services Resource Institute Presents a Conference and Workshop on: Sexual Abuse of Children, East Brunswick, NJ, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Human Resources Series: Sexual Exploitation of Children and Youth by Shelley Friend, Colorado State Legislative Report, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- How Can I Name It? or Cassandra Predicts the Past by Karen Lynn Peterson, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Child Sexual Exploitation: Background and Legal Analysis by the National Legal Resource Center for Child Advocacy and Protection, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Sexual Abuse and Maltreatment of Children: Identification and Management in Hospitals and Clinics, Official Guidelines of the New York State Department of Health and Department of Social Services (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Sexual Assault of Children and Adolescents prepared by Carolyn Swift for presentation to the Domestic and International Scientific Planning, Analysis, and Cooperation Subcommittee of the Committee on Science and Technology of the United States House of Representatives, NYC, NY, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- National TCI Implementation: Effectiveness Surveys (N=112) [in brown file folder] (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Seven Steps to the Life Space Interview (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Evaluation: Evaluating the Process and Product of Training (Box 6, Folder 17)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute (CPSTI), Therapeutic Crisis Intervention, Instructor's Manual, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Train the Trainer (working copy 1) (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Train the Trainer (working copy 2) (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Video Script: Crisis Intervention Training in Child Care, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Crisis Management Team, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Review and Assessment of the Crockett State School Crisis Management Team, Planning, Research, and Evaluation, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Active Listening documents (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Scripts for TCI Video (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Intervencion Terapeutica en Crisis (Therapeutic Crisis Intervention- Spanish translation), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Existing Restraint Techniques: Gentler Ways (Non-Abusive Physical and Psychological Intervention); Professional Growth Facilitators (Box 7, Folder 2)
- National Residential Child Care Project Brochure (Therapeutic Crisis Intervention, Investigation of Child Abuse and Neglect in Out of Home Care), Institutional Assessment), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- National Residential Child Care Project Brochure (Training of Trainers in Therapeutic Crisis Intervention), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Berskshire Farms (handwritten notes), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Incident Reporting, Investigating, and Monitoring Draft, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Instructions for Completing "Change Agent" Questionnaire (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Life Space Crisis Intervention: The Skill of Reclaiming Children and Youth With Self-Defeating Behaviors by Nicholas Long and Frank Fecser, Life Space Crisis Intervention Institute, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- National Conference on Institutional Child Abuse, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Protection of Children in Residential Care: A Study of Abuse and Neglect in Child Care Institutions in New York State by Senator Joseph Pisani, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Investigating Abuse (IAB) Resource Manual, by Michael Nunno, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Children's Rights Handbook: An Introductory Guide for Child Protection Professionals and Agencies by Claire Bedard, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Citizen's Guide to the Child Welfare Reform Act of 1979, Juvenile Justice Center, New York State, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Proposal for Voluntary Foster Care Placement and Review Proceedings in Family Court, New York State Temporary Commission to Recodify the Family Court Act (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Trends in the New York State Child and Foster Care Populations 1960 to 1980, Projections for 1985 and 1990, Estimates of Policy Impact (Box 7, Folder 4)
- New York State Child Protective Services, Mandated Reporter Manual, Volume 3, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Direction Paper: The Development of Preventative Services Program Standards in New York State, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- A Request for Support for the New York State Federation of County Task Forces on Child Abuse and Neglect (Concept Paper) by John Doris, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- A Guide to New York State's Child Protective Services Law Title 6 Article 6 Social Services Law (Slide Set Script) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with New York State Governor and Legislature concerning the Repot by the Temporary State Commission on Child Welfare entitled "Child Protective Services in New York State", 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Testimony before the Governor's Task Force on the Federal Human Services Budget, New York State Federation on Child Abuse and Neglect, Albany, NY, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, The Sexual Abuse Interview, Participant Guidebook, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Meaningful Communication with Children for Interviews, Direct and Cross-Examination: Law Guardian Training Seminar, Utica, NY, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- NATO (North Atlantic Treaty Organization) Advanced Studies Institute Programme: The Child Witness in Context: Cognitive, Social, and Legal Perspectives, Tuscany, Italy, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Drawer 3: National Programs & Proposals (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Correspondence with Arizona Department of Economic Security, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Child Protective Services Training Program, Arizona, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Seattle Training Center, Western Washington University, Washington, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- The Training Connection, Volume 1, Number 1, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Department of Children's Services Training Center, Los Angeles County, California, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Department of Training, School of Social Work and Community Planning, University of Maryland, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Social Counselor Certification Training Program: Overview, Tennessee, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Major Design Considerations Underlying the Development of the Florida Child Welfare Training Academy, Presented at the 111th Annual Conference if the American Association for Protecting Children, Inc., Austin, Texas, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- The Continuing Crisis: A Report on New York City's Response to Families Requiring Protective and Preventative Services by Brenda McGowan, Jeanne Bertrand, Amy Kohn, and Anne Lombard for the Neighborhood Family Services Coalition, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Family Day Care Homes, Regulations and Guidelines, New York State Department of Social Services (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Correspondence with Public Child Fatality Review Committee, New York State Department of Social Services, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Child Protective Services Academy, Nine Month Training Program, New Caseworkers, New York State, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Child Protective Services Training Academy: Final Report by Susan Notkin, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- New York State IOHC Guidebook, Week Two, by Michael Nunno, Nancy Fritsche, and Brian Bentley (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Investigation of CA/M In Out of Home Care Outline (Box 7, Folder 9)